# Khodar El-Helou

SYSTEM PROGRAMMING & CYBER SECURITY

## **PROFILE**

Motivated and passionate 23-year-old Computer Science graduate that loves to continuously learn and develop new skills. I consider myself well-versed in Web and Mobile Application Development as I have strong knowledge using Object-Oriented Programming and Data Structure Algorithms within my code.

#### CONTACT

PHONE: (+61) 414 104 080

#### WEBSITE:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/khodar-el-helou-20b281169/

#### EMAIL:

khodarelhelou@gmail.com

## **HOBBIES**

- Writing code
- Reading books
- Listening to music
- Designing art
- Soccer and basketball

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Green Valley Islamic College**

2003 - 2016

Performed and completed my Primary and Higher School education at Green Valley Islamic College. Graduated with an ATAR of 84.10

### **Western Sydney University**

2017 - 2020

Studied Bachelor of Computer Science at Kingswood WSU. Majored in System Programming and Cyber Security with an GPA score of 4.625

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# White Flame Creative (Work Experience)

10/2013 - 11/2013

- Interpersonal skills among team members
- Time management
- Designed graphics for small businesses and private organisations

# **Just 4 Kids Tutoring (Casual)**

01/2018 - 11/2019

- Review and mark student assignments and homework
- Educate students with new concepts in Math, English, Science, and Information Technology
- Taught students to respect their teachers and peers

#### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

# Health and Well-being Mobile Application Evaluation (HaWMAE)

- Front-end: Design the layout and functionality of the website
- Back-end: Connected website to server and connect the website to a database to transmit and receive information
- Developed the following functionalities: Account creations, login/register, request accounts, CRUD projects and surveys, view data in bar/line/pie charts, download data to excel file, send email invitation and many more.
- Connected the website to servers and managed all the backend data being stored onto the database
- Leader within the team and compiled all other group members tasks into one project
- Assisted team members with tasks and fixed project errors
- Error checking to make sure system does not experience crashes or bugs

# **SKILLS**

## **Programming Languages**

- HTML
- JavaScript
- C
- XML
- CSS
- Java
- C#Kotlin
- PHP
- C++
- Swift
- Visual Basic

## Strengths

- Team orientated
- Attention to detail
- Love of learning
- Time and task management
- Leadership skills
- Working under pressure
- Supreme communication skills
  - Big-picture focus

## **REFERENCES**

References will be provided upon requests.